

HILMAN FIRDAUS, S.KOM

GITHUB : hilman-firdd (Hilman Firdaus) (github.com)

GITLAB : https://gitlab.com/hilman-firdd
LINKEDIN. : (24) Hilman Firdaus | LinkedIn
Portfolio. : portfolio.hilfideveloper.com
EMAIL : hilmanfirdaus48@gmail.com

WA/TELP. : 081914209656

Summary

Graduated from Nurtanio University, with cumlaude predicate, GPA 3.69. I have 8++ years of experience in the field of Technology Software Engineer, if hands on in the field of Quality Assurance (QA) 5 and developer in field frontend also backend in a company which requires me to remain in the corridor of contributing my skills towards technology progress in the software industry internationally and finance.

My focus is now on being a quality engineer, with my current position, I prefer preventing bugs before production release and also collaborating on early bug prevention. And I have a keen eye for detail and a commitment to ensuring products or services reach the highest quality standards.

Education

Bachelor Degree - Engineering Informatics, NURTANIO UNIVERSITY - Bandung (2017 -2021). GPA 3.69

Work Experiences

Changle Singapore Project (Februari-Mei 2024)

An application that provides various services such as reservations, travel, ordering food, etc. and is wrapped in an attractive appearance so that it invites visitors and is interested in changing the application. Changle Hotel Reservasi

- Update bugs or findings bug or Create TC using Excel
- SIT, UAT, Regression, And Production manual testing, based on desktop, CMS and Mobile Responsive categories
- Creating test scenarios using Excel spreadsheets based on FSD and Figma UI/UX
- Understanding flow project with BRD and coordination with Business Engineer and Lead Squad
- Testing Automation tools Selenium Java UI only
- Implementation Strategi Testing, Exploration test, Regression test, Smoke test, E2E test
- Working Blackbox testing, in case Whitebox testing

PT Astra Internasional Tbk (September-Februari 2024)

Astra offers a variety of choices and the latest models of motorized vehicles according to consumer needs. Astra produces, assembles, distributes and has a dealer network for Toyota, Daihatsu, Isuzu, Peugeot, UD Trucks and Honda motorbikes. Astra also produces and is a retailer of BMW and Lexus cars.

Project Auto2000 (November-Desember 2023)

- Update bugs using Azzure Tools
- Carry out performance tests using the Jmeter tool
- Creating test scenarios using Excel spreadsheets based on FSD and Figma UI/UX notions
- SIT, UAT, Regression manual testing, based on desktop, CMS and Mobile Responsive categories
- Testing Automation tools Katalon Studio
- SEO testing using gtmetrix, Rich results test, lighthouse, seo meta and disable javascript
- Performs Testing with Apache Kafka

PT Moladin Digital Indonesia (April-Agustus 2023)

Moladin has built the entrepreneurial spirit of its agents with its fast-growing network, involving more than 100,000 agents and dealers by creating a comprehensive digital automotive platform and providing best-inclass training, assistance and support.

My Responsibilities:

- Developing and maintaining test plans and test cases for software applications.
- Executing manual tests to ensure the quality and functionality of software applications.
- Identifying, troubleshooting, and documenting defects in software applications.
- Working closely with developers to resolve defects and improve the quality of the software.
- Collaborating with other QA engineers to review and improve the testing process.
- Create testing API with Postman
- Do research Automation using Playwright
- Report test ops in Allure

PT Hilfi Dev Technology (September 2022 - Mei 2023)

SpeedCash (Desember-Januari 2022)

is an application, for those of you who want to travel by plane, making a plane ticket reservation in advance is the best way to secure the departure or schedule you want.

My Responsibilities:

- Do Perform API Testing on Microservices/Rest API.
- Define, Analyze Requirement for implement to Test Scenario in Testrail or Spreadsheet
- Do research Automation using Katalon(intermediete) & Cypress
- Monitoring Story/task/bugs using Jira & Trello.
- Do Perform Functional Testing in Website, Progresive Web Application, Mobile Applications

Anaonline.id Management system (Januari-Maret 2023)

is an application for managing special systems for youth exactly, such as membership and special applications

My Responsibilities:

- Do Perform API Testing on Microservices/Rest API.
- Define, Analyze Requirement for implement to Test Scenario in Spreadsheet
- Do research Automation using Webriver.io typescript mocha & chai
- Monitoring Story/task/bugs using Gitlab and Circle Cl.
- Do Perform Functional Testing in Website, Progresive Web Application, Mobile Applications

Simasis, Management system (April-Mei 2023)

is an application for managing special systems for youth exactly, such as membership and special applications

My Responsibilities:

- Define, Analyze Requirement for implement to Test Scenario in Spreadsheet
- Do research Automation using Selenium javascript, mocha & chai
- Monitoring Story/task/bugs using Gitlab and Circle Cl.
- Do Perform Functional Testing in Website
- Do Perform function Testing third party, in Midtrans.

PT Telekomunikasi Indonesia (Juni 2019 - Agustus 2022)

Dunia Games (Juni-Agustus)

is a site that provides various user needs related to games offered by PT. Cellular Telecommunications (TELKOMSEL). Access to Dunia Games can be done through the website www.duniagames.co.id and applications available on the Android OS and Apple iOS platforms on your smartphone. The terms & conditions stipulated below givern the use of Dunia Games, both the use the www.duniagames.co.id website and the Dunia Games Applications.

My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (native & hybrid)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation Testing in API, web, mobile Using Katalon & Postman
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Perform E2E Testing & Regression Testing in our project
- Report tase case in jira tools

MEA & MEC (Agustus-Oktober)

is application to manage and monitor field workers, with a cloud-based mobile application to manage and monitor field workers, and improve communication between workers wherever they are using field force management.

My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (web automation)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation Testing in API, web Using Katalon
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Report tase case in jira tools

99Usahaku (November-Januari)

99% of My Business was developed to support the growth of Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) in Indonesia. SMEs can use 99% Usahaku as a platform for sales.

My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (web automation)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story

- Perform Automation, web Using Katalon
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Report tase case in jira tools

FUT Home LTE (My Orbit) (Februari-April)

Telkomsel Orbit is an all-digital home internet service provider in Indonesia that uses WiFi modem devices.

My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing mobile application (web automation)
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation, web Using Katalon
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Report tase case in jira tools

Elisa (Januari-Februari)

Elisa is apps for support service payment gateway, like as dana, shopee, midtrans etc.. My Responsibilities:

- Perform automated testing web application project.
- Perform automated testing with API, using katalon
- Raise bugs & feedback to engineer teams in our sprint development
- Review requirement & spesification for create acceptance testing in User Story
- Perform Automation, web Using Katalon
- Writing & Review acceptance test in User Journey
- Report tase case in jira tools

PT WGS Bandung, (November 2016 - Desember 2017)

Front End Developer

WGS is one of the largest IT services company in Indonesia, offering programmer outsourcing, custom pre-packaged business software, and enterprise

- Created 10+ templates web used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap with responsive design.
- Analyze, design, develop web, as well as implement RESTful services and APIs
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues, and solving clients problems
- Collaborate with a multidisciplinary team of UI/UX Designers, Back-end Developers, System Analysts to complete projects

Skills set and Expertise

#Katalon #Cypress #Javascript #Selenium #Typescript #Java #E2ETesting #PostgresSql
#Jira #Agile #RegressionTesting #SIT-UAT-REGRESI-SANITY #SmokeTesting #LoadTesting
#jMeter #WebDriver #ApiTesting #Bitbucket #AllureTestOps #Playwright #MobileTesting
#blackBox #whiteBox #confluenceDokumentation #excelReport #SDLC #STLC #pipeline
#Jenkins #gitlabCICD

SERTIFICATION NAME	Sponsor by
Postman API Testing Workshop International	STAD Solution
Linux Fundamentals	ID-Networkers (IDN.ID)
Manual Testing	STAD Solution
ISTQB® Foundation Level (Acceptance Testing)	ISTQB® - International Software Testing Qualifications Board
Microsoft Office Specialist Master Certification (MOS)	Microsoft
MikroTik Certified Network Associate	MikroTik
Pemograman Python	Dicoding Indonesia
Java Language Programming	Sololearn
Javascript Language Programming	Dicoding Indonesia
Quantum Computing and Communication Technologies	Institut Teknologi Bandung
Responsive Web Design	Sololearn
Developing SQL Databases	Sololearn

(24) Licenses & certifications | Hilman Firdd | LinkedIn

Languages

- English
- Arab
- Indonesia